I took two calculator type quizzes to
figure out my slavery footprint and my
carbon footprint and it turns out under
rough estimation I have 33 slaves and
ten tons of carbon in order to be
ethical to not be using more than my
share to not be I need that number to be
at zero slaves clearly zero is the
number we need to reach for and from the
person who posted the calculator is
three tons of carbon per person so if
you're above that you should be bringing
it down if you're below it you should I
don't know if you should be bringing it
up but like you're allowed to bring it
up to be fair the issue is when I took
the quiz I don't I don't fly I fly less
than once a year I Drive a car because I
have to for my health condition and also
poverty because I don't have the money
to pay for bus fare on one-off basis
when I'm already paying for insurance on
my car if there is a parking it's
cheaper to drive than it is to pay for a
bus so my finances have to come into
play all the time and there's a lot of
times where I cannot take the bus so
food you know I don't have access to
organic food I can't allow me to have
access to it you notice I'm at closing
and stuff but it's not in my price point
I can't buy Fairtrade clothing I can't
do the things that would make it so that
I have less slaves I can't do the things
that make it so I have less carbon
output or can offset the carbon I could
probably be doing more than I am but I
cannot tackle those two numbers on my
own what we can do together is look at
where those numbers came from how do i
transport myself in a way that works for
me and my conditions without offsetting
those externalities onto other people
especially slavery and it's the only way
is to do it is together how do we tackle
the food system how do we tackle having
clothes to wear
and transportation and heating my home I
live in Canada
you know in parts of our country it's
negative 40 negative 34 large parts of
the year and below that up north like so
even if we move to everyone to our
southern border where they kind of do
live already it's still cold for large
parts of the year we still have to heat
our home so instead of making it
individual consumers who have to solve
this problem the eye and without needing
it to be the them the big carbon offsets
the government needs to change the
corporations need to stop doing it
there's a space in between where we can
solve it together we can figure out
modes of transportation we can figure
out a food system that does not require
literally feeding off of other humans
labor treating them as commodity and
benefiting from it out of ignorance and
the same with the planet in carbon but
nor can we ask everyone to wake up to
that fact when we don't have anywhere to
lead them this is poor against poor sick
against sick I don't have an option to
not have those things to not have I mean
I might be able to bring my slavery
number down to 15 if I was really
conscious and and and capable there's
nowhere to buy electronic cuz it doesn't
include slavery the food system and
clothing systems that are ethical aren't
accessible to me and so these are things
we have to tackle together we have to be
able to look at what is our actual
footprint and how do we we get would
make it better but if all we're doing is
telling people with their footprint is
so they can feel bad in my experience
that leads to chronic illness and I
don't want the world to be chronically
ill because that's just more of a
snowball more stuff to have to put on
you and deal with we need solutions and
they're not going to come from the
marketplace because the marketplace is
what kind of created these problems
together we can create things that
out-compete the marketplace and don't
create the crap that they are creating
we don't we do not design them to
out-compete the marketplace we designed
them to be natural attractors to be
invitation we design solutions that are
so amazing maybe they start a little
less amazing
but they're so amazing that they
naturally attract people in and we're
continually improving them so I have 33
slaves and 10 tons of carbon and I need
your help I need your help to reduce
that and I will like both of those
calculators in the comments if you
happen to want to find out what your
footprint is and if we can create a way
to collectively bring our numbers down
until we get to zero slaves and three
tons of carbon thank you